<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellany on The Subtlety</title>
    <link>https://www.thesubtlety.com/categories/miscellany/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellany on The Subtlety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:27:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.thesubtlety.com/categories/miscellany/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenDNS&#39;s AppSec Training Lab</title>
      <link>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/opendnss-appsec-training-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/opendnss-appsec-training-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across OpenDNS Security Ninjas AppSec &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opendns/Security_Ninjas_AppSec_Training&#34;&gt;Training Lab&lt;/a&gt; not too long ago and found its simplicity rather enjoyable. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple web app written in PHP which illustrates each of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10_2013-Table_of_Contents&#34;&gt;OWASP Top 10&lt;/a&gt; categories. As I was going through the exercises I found myself checking to see how the vulnerable code was written and how the issues could be remediated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the lab is geared towards beginners, I thought it might be helpful to provide brief explanations along with links to the relevant lines of source code. For each level/OWASP vulnerability, I simply added a &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo; section to each &amp;ldquo;Solution&amp;rdquo; area linking to the sink on Github along with a brief explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The merge request is apparently pending an OpenDNS maintainer, but the fork is on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thesubtlety/Security_Ninjas_AppSec_Training&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renewing your StartCom SSL Cert</title>
      <link>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/renewing-your-startcom-ssl-cert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/renewing-your-startcom-ssl-cert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten how to do this over the past year, here are the directions for posterity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Startcom sends you a reminder after 50 weeks and opens a window for a renewal. Log in and validate your email and domain using the Validation Wizard. Note, you need to ensure your email is going to forward properly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generate a key and CSR on the server with the following two commands
&lt;code&gt;openssl genrsa -out ./www.thesubtlety.com.key 2048&lt;/code&gt; 
&lt;code&gt;openssl req -new -key www.thesubtlety.com.key -out www.thesubtlety.com.csr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once your domain is validated by StartSSL, you need to request a new certificate which is pretty self explanatory. Use the Certificate Wizard, follow the prompts, and paste in the CSR where asked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got that, copy it to a .crt file on the server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the chain file. This can be created by cat-ing the files ca.pem and sub.class1.server.ca.pem &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.startssl.com/certs/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; into a .chn file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NFS SSL help and request link is here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://members.nearlyfreespeech.net/username/support/assist?tag=ssl&#34;&gt;https://members.nearlyfreespeech.net/username/support/assist?tag=ssl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, verify the newly installed cert is updated with a new expiration date.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Random Ramblings</title>
      <link>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/random-ramblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 21:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/random-ramblings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here, shall I attempt to document some random doings related to computers, security, linuxstuff, windowsstuff, and most likely miscellany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently typing all this out helps the mind become better at communicating, and who doesn&amp;rsquo;t want that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So whether you or another read these ramblings, or I myself re-read them later on in my ever so awe-inspiring, galvanic, exhilarating life, let this be a place for learning and perusing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>