<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on The Subtlety</title>
    <link>https://www.thesubtlety.com/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on The Subtlety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 17:19:40 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thesubtlety.com/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Persistent C2 with dnscat2</title>
      <link>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/persistent-dnscat2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 17:19:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/persistent-dnscat2/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally an environment has strict outbound rules with all traffic going through an authenticated proxy. This hampers exfiltration, especially if you don&amp;rsquo;t currently have valid credentials but need a foothold into an environment without phishing for instance. If we can find a live network jack in some accessible place and the switch hands out an IP address via DHCP along with DNS servers, we can more than likely obtain a foothold into the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenDNS&#39;s AppSec Training Lab</title>
      <link>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/opendnss-appsec-training-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/opendnss-appsec-training-lab/</guid>
      <description>I came across OpenDNS Security Ninjas AppSec Training Lab not too long ago and found its simplicity rather enjoyable. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple web app written in PHP which illustrates each of the OWASP Top 10 categories. As I was going through the exercises I found myself checking to see how the vulnerable code was written and how the issues could be remediated.
Since the lab is geared towards beginners, I thought it might be helpful to provide brief explanations along with links to the relevant lines of source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OSCP | Penetration Testing With Kali Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/the-oscp-penetration-testing-with-kali-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 22:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/the-oscp-penetration-testing-with-kali-linux/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last few months working through the Penetration Testing with Kali Linux course by Offensive Security which has been an awesome learning experience.
Much has been said on this course and I&amp;rsquo;ll only briefly go over my experience and takeaways. The following reviews were helpful in making the decision to take the course.
 Review by g0tmi1k Review by recrudesce Review from Buffered.io Review from IODigitalSec Review from SecuritySift   For a little preview of what&#39;s involved, check out the free [Metasploit Unleashed](http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Web App in Rails</title>
      <link>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/building-a-web-app-in-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 01:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thesubtlety.com/post/building-a-web-app-in-rails/</guid>
      <description>A brilliant software engineering friend and I were recently discussing with another mutual friend the inefficiencies of employees filling out paper forms after completion of a construction job and the inefficiencies of transferring said forms to excel and so on. Said friend and I figured we could probably fix this with a web app for a nominal fee, but which would greatly increase our mutual friends&#39; productivity. A win win situation if there ever was one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
